IGUNMA GOODNESS OSAKPAWAN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Creative software engineer with a strong focus on developing visually appealing and efficient web applications that drive user growth and engagement. Highly skilled in translating designs into functional code and collaborating on solutions with Product Owners, Quality Assurance (QA) Engineers, and Server-Side teams to offer the best user experience to build higher customer lifetime value.

EXPERIENCE

Interswitch Group, Lagos — FRONT END ENGINEER

May, 2022 - April, 2023.

Tasks

- Applied pragmatism and best practices in software engineering, delivering tasks on time, and with excellent quality.
- Experience with Rest APIs to fetch data and managing of state with Redux Toolkit.
- Worked in an agile environment (SCRUM, KANBAN, JIRA)
- Fixed bugs on Local Machine, UAT(User Acceptance Test), and on Production.
- Worked on existing React codebase to add new features using both functional and class-based components.

Syborf Business Venture, Benin City — JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Oct, 2021 - Jan, 2022

Tasks

- Performed code reviews to encourage quality, reusable, and more efficient code.
- Worked with Objected Oriented Programming in PHP with the WAMP stack(Windows, Apache, MySQL &PHP) and MVC(Model, View, Controller) framework Laravel. Successfully building an Employee Management System.

Freelancing, Benin City — *JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER*

Jan, 2020 - Oct, 2021

Tasks

 Translated Figma designs and prototypes into pixel-perfect User Interfaces.

CONTACT

Email:

goodnessigunma1@gmail.com

Address:

Yaba, Lagos.

Phone No:

+234-8108251426

PORTFOLIO

GitHub:

https://github.com/igudy

Personal Website:

(See all live project here)
https://igudy-react-portfol
io-2022.vercel.app/

Linkedin:

https://linkedin.com/in/goodness-igunma-65bb581a7

EDUCATION

Oct, 2016 to Jul, 2021 COMPUTER SCIENCE University Of Benin Second Class Upper(2.1)

CERTIFICATIONS

Feb, 2022 to Feb, 2023 NATIONAL YOUTH SERVICE CORPS

Dec, 2022

INTERSWITCH ACADEMY ENGINEERING DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM Interswitch Group

Jun, 2020

JAVASCRIPT AND JSON FOR WEB DEVELOPERS University of Michigan –

University of Micnigan -Coursera

- Writing unit, functional, and integration tests with RTL(React Testing Library), Jest, and Cypress thereby continually improving the web application.
- Front-end codes were developed in a timely and high-quality manner while maintaining a consistent look and feel.

Jul, 2020 BUILDING WEB APPLICATIONS IN PHP

University of Michigan -Coursera

PROJECTS

Quickteller Homes - https://homes.quickteller.com (Live Link)

Worked with a team of software engineers to develop the Quickteller homes web application.

- Implemented the UI for the Admin Dashboard Page using React, Material UI, and React Bootstrap
- Implemented the modal and carousel component (UI and Logic) using ReactJS, SASS, and React Carousel on the product listing details page.
- REST API calls to display data from endpoints.

Igshop (E-Commerce Web Application)

https://igshop.vercel.app(Live Link)

E-commerce web app built with React, Redux Toolkit, and Firebase(authentication and storage). The backend server is built with Node and ExpressJS. This web app features the following;

- Stripe for payment integration
- React ChartJS 2 for admin charts
- React Country Region Selector for country selection
- React Star Rate for reviews

Evogym - https://evogym-bice.vercel.app/(Live Link)

This is a landing page for a gym built with React and TypeScript, with a modern design using Heroicons for icons and Framer Motion for animations. Styling is done with Tailwind, providing a clean and responsive layout.

Employee Management System

<u>https://github.com/igudy/employees-management-syste</u> (Github Link)

Employee Management Web Application built with Laravel 8, API, VUE. JS, and Bootstrap 4 Framework, as well as libraries like Moment JS, Vue-Router and Vuejs Datepicker for selecting dates.

SKILLS & TOOLS

Programming

- CSS Flexbox & Grid
- React Bootstrap
- Tailwind
- Javascript
- Typescript
- ReactIs
- Redux
- Redux Toolkit
- Next JS
- Node JS
- Express JS
- PHP(Laravel)

Design

- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop

SOFT SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- Team Player
- Time management
- Communication
- Leadership

LANGUAGE(S)

• English Language

INTEREST

- Football
- Gaming
- Reading